The game is based on a network power scale. More players, more total power.

The structure of stages is freeform.
	Entry
	Main
		Battle
		Reward
	Boss
		Retreat
		Capture

Entry
On entry the players reveal their outer equipment
The discussion may begin immediately depending on distraction levels
	distraction level = the time in seconds required for a player to take an action
	discussion = any texting or direct chat
If an immediate aggression breaks out among players then everyone will declare alliegence
	alliegence = solitary power level, determined by the player on a tie, determined by the game when alliegence points exceed opponent by 2.
	

Main
The main stage of the game consists of dungeon traversal with small rooms that limit the number of players who may access.

The two closest players may be forced to cooperate, but it is frequently more rewarding to argue and battle.

Conditions which trigger the argument are such
	Feelings of fear
	Distrust
		A risk of losing a reward to theft
		Lack of cooperation
	Tension between the two cooperatives
	Complex emotions
	

Battle
A battle is pvp while in the main stage, while in Boss stage the battle is pve.

PVP battle
A number of actions may fit into one or several categories
	Active = demand power
		Physically attacking or threatening your opponent.
	Passive = deny the opponent leeway while posturing for greater power
		Conning your opponent, appearing more competent.
		Misleading your opponent to believe they are at a disadvantage.
		Failing to communicate important clues.
	Submissive = perform an action to allow the opponent leeway
		Grant your opponent power immediately for a chance to end the confrontation, first strike opportunity is granted on next turn.
	Evasive = Avoid the confrontation
		Leaving the room 
		Ending a conversation early
		Continuing progress in the stage to a conclusion, ending the confrontation.
		
PVE battle
The purpose would be to test players in an impossibly difficult scenario.
The scenario would range from simple to abstract nonsense.

A few easy examples
	A puzzle
	A Trap
	A cage
	A question

A few abstract (difficult) examples
	A vote
	A devil which grants extra power, the devil must be defeated but the extra power opens up PVP battles against the player commands.
	A shocking discovery. A gauntlet of inquiry about said discovery turns the others against them.
	
Retreat
In almost every case the players may retreat individually or as a group (when cooperation to escape is necessary). A power loss may incur on individuals.
	
Reward
In every case there will be a power reward to successful players.