this is what you're missing

[family]
phobia of car rides
getting ignored because you have inconvenient time critical needs
phobia of old relatives
accusations for getting out of a seat, or falling asleep (your parents are just fucked up)
accused of hating your mother by your mother, between ages 0 and 3
claims that your life was saved, also between ages 0 and 3
your fear reflex is overstimulated for the amusement of others fuck you kid
you're in the way if someone's busy
you're dangerous if you're too quiet
nobody can hear you when you have an answer
oh but that kid heard you and gets to whine
your parents don't really know how to raise you, it's just a part time job
your parents need to grow up
[/family]