The schools I'm aware of are daycares. 
The kids go there and get watched
the school's responsible if a kid exhibits free will
they're also a competitive business model that really doesn't want to be

This obviously fails for students who seek skills. early on, I was told some generic wait your turn pitch. There is no option.  But the truth is higher education is about as real as high society, you're learning complicated behaviors, not learning to think for yourself. Learning not to think for yourself can be a challenge when the people who do exploit you anyways.

This fails for competitive animals, the work is mostly secretive and incoherent, so they turn their attention to social entertainment, which carries weight outside school.
