Better tutorial?

Or better Feedback?

Feedback purpose
	tell player what's going on
	
Tutorial purpose
	tell player how to do
	
Introduce
	Mysterious
	De-myst
	Normal
	Mundane
	Reuse
	Tool
	
In tutorial focus
	[you can see you're in a bowling alley, whatever that is]
	Hey this is a bowling ball
	roll the ball at pins
	go
	
	later you see a bowling ball, but there are no pins
	Hey this is a bowling ball
	roll it at random things
	
In feedback focus
	In bowling alley
	there is bowling ball
	there are pins
	
	indicate the ball STRONGLY
	indicate the pins WEAKLY
	have EVERYTHING respond to the throw, what you hit moves
	
In introduction focus
	The alley is mundane, reused
	The bowling ball is mysterious
		It can be mysterious a while
	It is basically a smooth rock with holes drilled in it
	There are a few dozen on a rack
	It's for throwing
	Other things are like bowling balls