This denotes play that does not have a structure, but it may be considered a form of exploration and discovery.

This is a microcosm of the experimentation phase during redundancy.

When mastery is nearly achieved there is no longer a reason to 'introduce' new concepts of the mastered subject. When the known mnemonics are uninteresting or overused they become like playthings. A beginner that memorized a subject can not distinguish between this phase and simple rote learning without having mastered art as a creative endeavor.

Finally, outside of an education and scholastic context this is the only form of play that has a fighting chance.

You either get lucky, or you know what you're doing. In the end, understanding how to and actually doing something are nothing alike. Learning from a textbook without learning to apply a skill is worthless, it's worth about as much as the paper it's written on if you tried to sell it.

Freeform play can only be called play when it's in a safe context, otherwise it's survival.