The oo design is about communicating objects. This is how I usually see an oo program now.

a hierarchy
hub
	object
	object
	
the objects communicate through a hub in a list because they can easily find it, going up the hierarchy is faster than searching through all the children.

object
	component
	component
	
the objects have component scripts, those do the work and more importantly you can reference the object they're on, and find the hub.


the object hierarchy is a physical representation like any part of a scene

the hierarchy
the 2D scene
the 3D scene

Variables are set if they meet criteria. Callbacks are triggered for the same reason.

----------

What is the difference when extending code?

Problem: I want to make a unique object.

1 change a variable, provided that variable is exposed. Done? (I'm not going to remember in a month)
2 inherit the class, and hardcode the variable, add a comment.

class MyNewClass: MyInheritedClass
{
	OnInit(){
		name = "Important"; // this class is important and I want the object's name to be changed to important
	}
	
}

If someone did this, they're oo programming.