There's a tldr conclusion at the end, enjoy.

I think all the information I've been researching about hidden tutorials in games has become a fundamental form of pedagogy, separate but not too different from the basic intro, body, conclusion formulae of a school textbook.

The four step story design is just a fundamental, and I've done much writing to describe the progress of a game after relearning this.

The teaching sequence of the story format described for games in various media are : introduce, explore, test, conclude.
The primary sequence of school textbook examples is : introduce the lesson, introduce the chapter, segment the chapter into sections, conclude, review... a few days later you get a test... a few days later you get a grade.
The primary sequence of a written document we're trained to be comfortable with writing in school are: intro, body, conclusion

Here are some notes I took while watching videos:
4 [] design? Looks like it's the way people naturally learn, determine information is useful, and feel good they remembered. - paraphrased from Mark Brown

THE 4 STEPS IN VARIOUS PHRASES
STEP 0.8 - courtesy of the hero's journey

passive unmotivated character development
1 do what you're told...
2 avoid danger
3 live within your means

STEP 1
1 become aware  
2 informed
3 introduced directly to a change
4 explore
STEP 2
1 gather information
2 gather things
3 get better
4 practice
5 granted many tries in quick succession
6 escalation

STEP 3
1 show you understand
2 knowledge of the world, system, mechanics
3 exploit
4 a twist
5 another change
6 all prior knowledge required now
7 extend step 2

STEP 4
1 final
2 exterminate a danger
3 back to rest
4 extend step 3

4 TYPES OF QUEST
introduce
expansion - gather... things or information
understanding - interact, defend
execution - kill quests


KI SHOU TEN KETSU
concept / hook
challenge iteration
test understanding with a twist
finish

4 RTS (ok this came from https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6luOrhlzvrc?)
explore
expand
exploit
exterminate

4 STEP MECHANIC
explore
introduce
make difficult
test


4 ?
explore
understand
leverage
bring together


info courtesy of:
a bunch of 1-1 mario videos like this:
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZH2wGpEZVgE?

Mark Brown: His channel has... much related info
 
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dBmIkEvEBtA?
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JqHcE6B4OP4?
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7daTGyVZ60I?

(edit1)the 4x rts reference came from another video I couldn't find right away.
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6luOrhlzvrc?

redundant school textbooks (Huh?)

tldr; The four step design is similar to textbook examples. But utilizes interaction and testing and feedback deliberately with accute directness and accuracy not available to schools, causing game pedagogy to heighten the natural learning rate, with almost no human failure rate.  This also makes it pretty damn obvious games teach players, and they teach them versatility.

afterword
I went on to learn more resources describing escalating mechanics, versatility, etc. But I think I actually reached the point I can't learn anything more, and I've taken the four steps and molded them like 4X gameplay from my notes several times. If anyone has a question or some interesting info about the four step design, please comment.

please feel free to comment or criticize, I don't have anything to add atm... so you'll give me an excuse to respond