Learning methods! A highly opinionated take on art science and the media condensed into a somewhat persuasive outline, read at your own risk.

Hey so I thought I'd add something I thought of recently. I was starting to use flash cards and acknowledge the rote practice quickly drained me after not studying for a long time. Although this post I don't talk about video games nearly enough I'm getting back into trying to understand how learning creates a bottleneck slowing progress, other stimuli may as well, but the subject here is learning. Ultimately how can I use it as a means of enhancing the player's perception? One day that could be answered.  This is more like a brainstorm session

I only have two answers,
1 media introduces someone to a subject, and they decide if they like it based on That Media. It's pure psychological warfare, devoid of reality, until they decide if they want to take a risk and look into it.

2 Dilemma: there's this new thing my brain can't recognize. I can't stand it longer than 2 minutes without a break. My life depends on it, and it changes nothing. Solution: Pacing and common ground is crucial, common ground is simple as stopping to rest or more complex like flow state.

Now for a bunch of details for anyone interested in my self reflection that brought me to the above statement.

-=define
learning - psychology. a semi-permanent change in behavior.
...your body or brain changes, so you learned something, and you can change it back or temporarily lose any evidence of change, that is the hidden meaning.

There are only two halves of learning I will address, Introductory and various methods that'll inevitably improve mastery

Methods of learning?

Introductory (or freeform): getting handed a mnemonic landmark you build off later

meme (aka random)- references scattered around media, can be iconic phrases, or styles, or various plot devices and themes of a story without a coherent linearity (I'm thinking of that hare* video).  A meme is like pasting someone's head on different bodies and seeing how fast one person's opinion will change.

art - 1 intentionally non-pragmatic, or unintuitive uses of a subject, resulting in imperfect models and tools. 2 the individual's expression of a subject master or not.

story (like, a movie or book) - influential, mnemonic, or emotional context of a subject is derived passively
... active participation like talking or playing a game involves mastery, it's even challenging for the people to participate in group activities this way, but I'm thinking it's a good introduction method


Mastery: as a goal oriented process, it involves gathering information of a subject, studying, playing, and practicing until the only challenge that remains is finding new information often succeeded by art

experienced learning - multiple introductions, information gathering, and exploitation of what you found (this is also )

practice method - there is a predetermined goal, reach said goal, rest, and repeat for a brief time (recommended limit max 40 minutes session, 240 minutes per day)

group (aka academic) - involves other participants with adequate preparation

science - develop or discover tools to accomplish a goal with greater ease, or fewer steps. may art


*hare video, hare of Inaba. I was thinking about if this could be a storied learning, and I concluded that in a patchwork pattern like this lacking coherence, it is essentially a modern meme.  Random elements of a story resembles real life more closely, memes trigger iconic memory, it's an anti-story.
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M53mGySTDN4?